# Howard Hamburger

**Data Scientist** 

#### **Personal Info**

**Address** 

4727 W. 147th Street Unit 201 Lawndale, CA 90260-1307

Phone

(818) 943-7892

E-mail

howard.hamburger@yahoo.com

LinkedIn

/www.linkedin.com/in/howard-hamburger-74890317/

#### **Skills**

Python, SQL, Jupyter Notebook,

Advanced

**Machine Learning** 

Advanced

Data Visualization

Advanced

Debugging

Expert

Data Mining

**Expert** 

**Problem Solving** 

**Expert** 

**Critical Thinking** 

Expert

**Creative Thinking** 

Expert

Interpersonal Skills

Advanced

Data Science Intern with 2 years experience with data mining, machine learning, data visualization, and large scale storage projects leading to the completion of a project that involved data mining of economic data, MapReduce, regular expressions and information extraction from Tweets using the UNIX command line in Spark and SQL features in Anaconda 3 Python all within an 8 week period.

## **Experience**

2018-03 -

#### **Data Analysis**

2018-05

Lewis University

- Project involving regular expressions, MapReduce using Spark HDFS, NLP, and SQL queries in Anaconda 3 Python of Tweets
- Created database of keywords from tweets and performed Sentiment Analysis on them
- Analyzed results for visualization purposes into pie charts and grouped charts into four different categories to see how Leading Economic Indicators relate to the specific tweets.

2004-04 -

2015-12

### **Analytical Audiologist**

Hear MD/Sharp Hearing/Audiology Consultants of Southern California

- Created thousands of linear regressions using an audiometer to classify
- residual hearing from hearing loss.

   Used Tensorflow-like evaluations with real ear measurement
- Used Tensorflow-like evaluations with real ear measurements to match the
  acoustics of a patient's ear canal to the target of the frequency response of the
  hearing aid using statistical functions from the manufacturer of the hearing aid.
- Used Otoacousic emission signals to data mine for specific frequencies of possible hearing loss in the cochlea of patients.

## **Education**

2016-08 -

## M.S. Data Science, Lewis University

2018-07

Excelled in Machine Learning and Data Science Coursework

- Completed Master's Thesis using President Trump's tweets and how the relate to Leading Economic Indicators using regular expressions, MapReduce, Sentiment Analysis, and SOL in Anaconda 3 Python.
- Completed all 12 courses in Data Science including Data Mining, Machine Learning, Statistical Programming, Data Visualization, Large Scale Storage, Distributed Computing Systems, Semantic Web, and Cyber Security.

2012-06 -

#### Au.D. Audiology, A.T. Still University

2014-09

Gained practical skills for clinical use in the field of Audiology GPA 4.0

0.7

1997-06 - M.S. Communication Disorders, California State University

Northridge

Major course work in Speech and Hearing Science, Advanced Audiology and Hearing Pathologies

375 clock hours completed in Audiology experience.

1993-02 -

B.S. Cell and Molecular Biology, California State University

1996-12 Northridge

1985-09 - **B.S. Computer Science, California State Polytechnic** 

1990-11 University Pomona